Bob Englehart Collection 2004.0026
Archives & Special Collections at the Thomas J. Dodd Research Center, University of Connecticut Libraries
Bob Englehart Collection
1987, 1991, 1995-1996, 2005-2009.
2004.0026
Archives & Special Collections at the Thomas J. Dodd Research Center, University of Connecticut Libraries
1.0 Linear feet
The collection contains original editorial cartoons drawn by Bob Englehart. The cartoons are generally 8.5 inches by 11.5 inches in size. An additional signed copy of a cartoon is also included.
Schorr, William M. [collector].
Wright, Dick [collector].
Biography
A native of Indiana, Bob Englehart studied at the American Academy of Art in Chicago before joining the staff of Chicago Today in 1966 as cartoonist and illustrator. In 1972, Englehart returned to Fort Wayne, Indiana as a free-lance artist for The Journal-Gazette. He became a full-time cartoonist in 1975 when he joined the staff of The Journal Herald ( Dayton, Ohio). In 1980, Englehart was hired as the first full-time editorial cartoonist for The Hartford Courant ( Hartford, Connecticut). Englehart's cartoons are now syndicated and he has published several collections of his editorial cartoons in addition to illustrating a children's book and providing television cartoon commentary.
Scope and Content
The collection contains the original artwork for editorial cartoons published in The Hartford Courant in 1995-1996, 2005-2009. A signed copy of a 1987 cartoon is also included.
Arrangement
The collection is chronologically arranged in one series.
Acquisition Information
The collection of original cartoons (1995) was donated by Dick Wright in 2004. The signed photocopy was donated by Norman Stevens in 2003. The more recent cartoons (2005-2009) were donated by William M. Schorr. Two framed cartoons were donated in 2012.
Related Material
Archives & Special Collections has a substantial collection of materials pertaining to Connecticut politics. For detailed information on these collections please contact the curator or ask at the Reading Room desk.
Access
The collection is open and available for research.
Englehart, Bob.; Cartoonist.; Cartoons, Editorial.; Illustrations (layout features).; Works of Art.
- Series I: Editorial Cartoons, 1987, 1991, 1995-1996, 2005-2009
  General note
  [Note: General topical descriptions for the cartoons have been supplied by the processor for access purposes only.]
  - Sports Center/Library funding, 1987 June (Box 2, Folder 21)
  - Mobile scud missile launcher, 1991 (Box 4, Folder 101)
  - Y'Know...You're really starting to get on my nerves (Middle East), 1991 (Box 4, Folder 102)
  - University of Connecticut Athletics, 1995 January 31 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - State Economy, 1995 February 3 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - John Rowland, 1995 February 22 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Weather, 1995 March 21 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - University of Connecticut Athletics, 1995 March 28 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Politics, 1995 April 19 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - John Rowland, 1995 June 1 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - State Legislature, 1995 June 9 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Affirmative Action, 1995 June 13 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Hartford Boys Academy, 1995 July 7 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Nancy Johnson, 1995 July 19 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - EAI, 1995 September 6 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Betty Crocker, 1995 September 13 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - World Conference on Women, 1995 Setpember 19 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Million Man March, 1995 September 27 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Middle East Peace Negotiations, 1995 October 1 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Lowell Weicker, 1995 November 9 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Nancy Johnson, 1995 November 28 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Department of Children and Families, 1995 December 15 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Nancy Johnson, 1995 December 19 (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Yale Unviersity labor, 1996 February 23 (Box 2, Folder 22)
  - Connecticut Science Center, 1996 February 25 (Box 2, Folder 23)
  - Hartford Democratic Town Committee Ballot, 1996 March 5 (Box 2, Folder 24)
  - Assisted Suicide/Bankruptcy, 1996 April 19 (Box 2, Folder 25)
  - Ethics ( Nancy Johnson), 1996 May 2 (Box 2, Folder 26)
  - Benjamin Netanyahu, 1996 June 2 (Box 2, Folder 27)
  - Ethics Report ( Nancy Johnson), 1996 September 6 (Box 2, Folder 28)
  - State Health Department, 1996 October 1 (Box 2, Folder 29)
  - African Crisis, 1996 November 3 (Box 2, Folder 30)
  - University of Connecticut budget, 1996 November 21 (Box 2, Folder 31)
  - George W. Bush Administration, 2005 November 3 (Box 1, Folder 32)
  - Walmart employment practices, 2005 November 4 (Box 1, Folder 33)
  - Gas Prices, 2005 November 6 (Box 1, Folder 34)
  - Jacques Chirac and French riots, 2005 November 9 (Box 1, Folder 35)
  - Kansas Board of Education (science), 2005 November 11 (Box 1, Folder 36)
  - Al-Qaida and Jordan bombings, 2005 November 13 (Box 1, Folder 37)
  - House of Representatives education funding cuts, 2005 November 15 (Box 1, Folder 38)
  - Iraq (Bush/Blair exit), 2005 November 16 (Box 1, Folder 39)
  - Samuel A. Alito nomination, 2005 November 17 (Box 1, Folder 40)
  - Medicare Prescription plan, 2005 November 18 (Box 2, Folder 41)
  - Bird Flu, 2005 November 24 (Box 2, Folder 42)
  - Gay Ban (Church), 2005 December 1 (Box 2, Folder 43)
  - Samuel A. Alito nomination, 2005 December 4 (Box 2, Folder 44)
  - Ann Coulter, 2005 December 6 (Box 2, Folder 45)
  - Saddam Hussein, 2005 December 9 (Box 2, Folder 46)
  - George W. Bush Foregin policy, 2005 December 14 (Box 2, Folder 47)
  - Iraq war spending, 2005 December 15 (Box 2, Folder 48)
  - Ban on torture, 2005 December (Box 2, Folder 49)
  - George W. Bush polls, 2005 December 20 (Box 2, Folder 50)
  - Spending Bills (ANWAR drilling/Defense), 2005 December 21 (Box 2, Folder 51)
  - "Presidential Fever" (Lieberman/Dodd), 2006 May 24 (Box 2, Folder 52)
  - Connecticut Yankee Nuclear Power Plant, 2006 July 28 (Box 2, Folder 53)
  - Governor's election (DeStefano, Rell, Malloy), 2006 July 30 (Box 2, Folder 54)
  - Hartford Housing Authority, 2006 September 14 (Box 2, Folder 55)
  - Governor's election (DeStefano, Rell), 2006 October 17 (Box 2, Folder 56)
  - Connecticut Courts, 2006 October 22 (Box 2, Folder 57)
  - Congressional election (Johnson, Murphy), 2006 October 27 (Box 2, Folder 58)
  - Hartford Housing Authority, 2006 November 12 (Box 2, Folder 59)
  - Congressional election (Courtney), 2006 November 16 (Box 2, Folder 60)
  - Magnet schools, 2006 December 5 (Box 2, Folder 61)
  - Connecticut State Police, 2006 December 6 (Box 2, Folder 62)
  - Iraq War, 2006 December 17 (Box 2, Folder 63)
  - Electric rates, 2006 December 19 (Box 2, Folder 64)
  - Nancy Pelosi amd Dick Cheney, 2007 January 7 (Box 3, Folder 65)
  - Holywood Writers strike, 2007 January 9 (Box 3, Folder 66)
  - State Senator Louis DeLuca resignation, 2007 November 15 (Box 3, Folder 67)
  - Barry Bonds, 2007 November 20 (Box 3, Folder 68)
  - Connecticut high school requirements, 2001 November 30 (Box 3, Folder 69)
  - Senator Christopher Dodd Presidential campaign, 2001 December 4 (Box 3, Folder 70)
  - Mitt Romney, 2007 December 11 (Box 3, Folder 71)
  - Right Wing, 2007 December 18 (Box 3, Folder 72)
  - Senator Joe Lieberman, 2007 December 19 (Box 3, Folder 73)
  - Ethics, 2007 December 13 (Box 3, Folder 74)
  - XL (Civic) Center, 2007 December 20 (Box 3, Folder 75)
  - Hartford Schools, 2007 December 21 (Box 3, Folder 76)
  - North Korea, 2009 July 31 (Box 3, Folder 77)
  - Connectcut state budget, 2009 September 27 (Box 3, Folder 78)
  - Michael Moore and Christopher Dodd, 2009 October 4 (Box 3, Folder 79)
  - Afghanistan and President Barack Obama, 2009 October 6 (Box 3, Folder 80)
  - Roman Polanski, 2009 October 7 (Box 3, Folder 81)
  - Church sex abuse coverup, 2009 October 8 (Box 3, Folder 82)
  - Health care reform, 2009 October 9 (Box 3, Folder 83)
  - Governor M. Jodi Rell, 2009 October 15 (Box 3, Folder 84)
  - President Barack Obama and Nobel Prize, 2009 October 11 (Box 3, Folder 85)
  - Rush Limbaugh, 2009 October 14 (Box 3, Folder 86)
  - Wall Street--Main Street, 2009 October 16 (Box 3, Folder 87)
  - Hartford gang problem, 2009 October 20 (Box 3, Folder 88)
  - Ron Paul, 2012 January 11 (Box 4, Folder 89)
  - Online gambling in Connecticut, 2012 January 13 (Box 4, Folder 90)
  - African American Legacy (MLK Day), 2012 January 15 (Box 4, Folder 91)
  - State pensions, 2012 January 25 (Box 4, Folder 92)
  - Leap Year, 2012 January 31 (Box 4, Folder 93)
  - Grote & Weigel, 2012 February 1 (Box 4, Folder 94)
  - Malloy School Plan, 2012 February 8 (Box 4, Folder 95)
  - Education Reform, 2012 February 23 (Box 4, Folder 96)
  - Bridgeport Schools, 2012 March 6 (Box 4, Folder 97)
  - Traffic Control, 2012 March 13 (Box 4, Folder 98)
  - Trinity College Security, 2012 March 16 (Box 4, Folder 99)
  - Gas Prices, 2012 March 30 (Box 4, Folder 100)